Dennou Boukenki
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Series Composition
Sekijima Mayori
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Takatori Hideaki
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Director
Okajima Kunitoshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Chief Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
저 건물은!
That building!
Bangunan itu!
미안, 눈부시지?
Sorry, it must have been too bright.
Maaf, terlalu silau, ya?
아니, 그냥 화장실. 아직 안 자, 쇼우?
Nah, I just wanted to go to restroom. Aren't you going to sleep soon?
Enggak, kok. Aku cuma mau ke toilet. Belum tidur, Shou?
응. 조금 이따가.
Yeah, later.
Iya. Sebentar lagi.
아, 뗏목이구나?
Is that for raft?
Ah, itu rakit, kan?
언젠간 필요할 거라 생각했어.
Thought this might be needed on a later time.
Kurasa suatu saat nanti, ini akan berguna.
대단해, 쇼우는!
You're awesome, Shou!
Shou keren sekali!
풍력으로 전기를 만들고!
Making electricity using the wind power!
Shou bisa membuat pembangkit listrik dengan tenaga angin!
아직 전구 하나 켜는 게 전부이긴 하지만.
It can only power up one bulb.
Baru bisa menyalakan satu lampu bohlam, sih.
바람이 없으면 어쩔 수 없어.
Without wind, it won't work.
Percuma saja kalau tidak ada angin.
모두에게 말할 거야. 쇼우는 믿을 수 있는 사람이라고. 나, 존경해!
Everybody said that we can depend on Shou. I respect you.
Semua bilang kalau kita bisa mengandalkan Shou. Aku sangat menghormatimu.
나도 같이 할래! 뗏목 만드는 거!
I'd like to make raft with you!
Oh, boleh aku ikut membantu membuat rakitnya?
카이토가? 그럼 편해지겠지.
You will? That should be some help.
Kaito mau? Aku akan sangat tertolong.
정말?
Really?
Benarkah?
-빨리 자.
-응!
-Go to sleep for now.
-I will!
-Cepat tidur, ya.
-Baik!
아, 화장실?
Toilet?
Jangan-jangan, mau minta ditemani?
혼자 가긴 무서워서...
Going to toilet by myself is scary...
Habis aku takut pergi sendiri...
서둘러, 쇼우! 간직한 우정
Hurry Up, Shou!
Friendship Deep Inside
Lekaslah, Shou! Persahabatan Tersembunyi
뗏목?
A raft?
Rakit?
응, 아침 일찍 둘이서...
Yeah, early in the morning those two went out together.
Iya, mereka berdua bergegas pergi tadi pagi.
꽉 묶어.
Tie it tight.
Ikat yang erat.
좋아, 됐어.
OK, that'll be it.
Ini sudah oke.
잠깐 쉬자. 카이토 덕분에 벌써 반 이상이나 만들었네.
Let's take a break. Thanks to your help, it's already half done.
Kita istirahat bentar, ya. Berkan bantuanmu, rakitnya sudah lebih dari setengah jalan selesai.
근데, 쇼우, 이 뗏목으로 어디 가게?
But where are you planning to go, Shou, with this raft?
Tapi, Shou, ingin kemana dengan rakit ini?
다이버랜드 교외에 큰 병원이 있는 거 알지?
You should saw a big hospital around Diverland.
Di sebrang Diverland ada rumah sakit yang besar, kan?
병원?
Hospital?
Rumah sakit?
어제 잠겨 있던 건물이 드러나는 걸 봤어.
I saw a sunken building yesterday.
Kemarin aku melihat sebuah bangunan tampak saat laut surut.
아, 어디? 어디야?
Where did you see that?
Ah, dimana itu?
저 쪽이야. 지금은 아직 바다에 잠겨 있지만.
That side. It under the sea for now, though.
Sekitar sini, tapi sekarang masih di bawah laut.
나 보러 갈래!
I'm going to take a look!
Aku mau lihat sebentar!
아직 안 보여! 소용 없을 텐데...
You can't see yet! You can see it after tide receded...
Masih belum tampak, loh! Lautnya belum surut...
정말 안 보이네.
There's really nothing...
Ah, iya, tidak ada apa-apa...
체크.
Check.
카이토!
Kaito!
카이토! 카이토!
Kaito! Kaito!
약이 없으니 상처를 치료할 수도 없는데... 카이토, 열도 나고 말이야.
We can't cure his wounds without a medicine... He's having a fever too.
Kita tidak bisa mengobati lukanya tanpa obat. Ditambah lagi, Kaito terkena demam.
-열은?
-내려갔어뾰꼬.
-How's the fever?
-It went down-pyoko.
-Bagaimana suhu badannya?
-Sudah menurun-pyoko.
보건실은 너무 많이 부숴져서 약은 죄다 사라졌어용.
The nurse's office is damaged too much and no medicine is there.
Ruang UKS rusak parah sehingga semua obatnya hancur-pyoko.
카이토...
Kaito...
찾아보자, 켄토! 약이 혹시 있을 지 모르니까 섬에서 찾아보자!
Let's go find some, Kento! Who knows there might be some medicine on the island!
Ayo kita cari obatnya secara menyeluruh di pulau ini, Kento!
그래, 다 같이 찾아보자!
Right, let's do it together!
Benar, mari berpencar dan cari obatnya!
아오이, 카이토 좀 봐줘.
Aoi, take care of Kaito.
Aoi, tolong urus Kaito.
힘내, 카이토. 꼭 약을 가지고 올게!
Keep there, Kaito. I'll return with the medicine.
Berjuanglah, Kaito. Aku pasti akan kembali dengan obatnya.
쇼우!
Shou!
뭐야, 이런 때 뗏목은 무슨! 뭔 생각이야, 대체? 불평하고 올 거야!
A raft, at a time like this? What is he thinking?! I'm going to complain to him!
Apa yang dia pikirkan, mengurus rakitnya di saat seperti ini?! Akan kumarahi dia!
-관둬, 나오키!
-카이토가 떨어졌을 때 쇼우가 같이 있었잖아!
-Don't, Naoki!
-Shou was together when Kaito fell off the clift!
-Hentikan, Naoki!
-Shou bersama dengan Kaito ketika dia terluka, kan?!
카이토가 떨어진 건 쇼우 때문이 아니잖아!
It's not Shou's fault that Kaito fell down!
Tapi luka Kaito bukan salah Shou!
그러니까 뭘 하고 있었는지 알아야 될 거 아냐! 카이토가 지금 얼마나 아파하는지 몰라서 그래?
And that's why we have to know what was he doing! Did you forget that Kaito is hurt?
Lalu apa maksudmu?! Kaito saat ini sedang menderita!
전기를 만든다니, 그게 뭐 그렇게 중요해? 쇼우가 그렇게 차가운 사람이었을 줄이야!
Making electricity, is that so important? Shou's so cold-hearted!
Memang membangkitan listrik sebegitu pentingnya, kah? Shou dingin sekali!
나오키! 일단은 약을 찾는 게 먼저야.
Naoki! Let's find the medicine first.
Naoki! Sekarang mencari obatnya lebih penting.
잠깐 와 봐!
Hey everyone!
Teman-teman!
쓰러진 이상 어떻게 구할 텐가?
It fell down, and how will it be saved?
Bagaimana mereka akan menyelamatkan pion yang terjatuh?
게임이 정말 재미있어지는군.
This is such an interesting game.
Permainannya tiba-tiba menjadi menarik.
어디 솜씨 한번 볼까, 켄토.
Let me watch your skill.
Kita lihat kemampuanmu, Kento.
약은?
Did you find it?
Bagaimana obatnya?
찾아볼 곳은 전부 다 찾아 봤어.
We searched every place possible.
Kita sudah mencari semua tempat yang mungkin.
켄토하고 카론은?
Where's Kento and Karon?
Dimana Kento dan Karon?
아직이야.
Not yet.
Mereka belum kembali.
역시 이 섬에는 약은 없는 걸까.
Is this island really without any medicine?
Sepertinya memang tidak ada obat di pulau ini.
형...
Brother...
Kakak...
켄토!
Kento!
일단 켄토는 돌아가뾰꼬. 카이토 곁을 지켜줘뾰꼬.
Kento should return first-pyoko.
Keep company and encourage Kaito-pyoko.
Lebih baik sekarang Kento kembali saja-pyoko. Temani Kaito dan dukung dia-pyoko.
젠장!
Damn!
Sial!
저건?
Look at that!
Itu, kan!
교외에 있던 병원이다!
A hospital around the city!
Itu rumah sakit yang ada di luar pulau!
썰물으로 모습이 드러났어뾰꼬!
It appeared thanks to the low tide-pyoko!
Bangunannya muncul saat air surut-pyoko!
병원? 그렇구나! 병원에 가면 약이 있지! 카이토를 구해줄 수 있겠어!
A hospital? That's it! Some medicines should be there and I'll be able to help Kaito!
Rumah sakit? Itu dia! Pasti ada obat di sana, dan Kaito bisa tertolong!
근데 어떻게 저기에 가게뾰꼬?
But how can we go there-pyoko!
Tapi, bagaimana kita bisa ke sana-pyoko?
쇼우!
Shou!
켄토!
Kento!
-아, 켄토!
-미안해, 쇼우.
-Hey, Kento!
-Sorry, Shou.
-Ah, Kento!
-Maafkan aku, Shou.
-어?
-뗏목을 만드는 건 바다에 잠긴 병원에 가기 위한 거였구나?
-Huh?
-I didn't knew you make the raft in order to go to that hospital.
-Eh?
-Rakit ini dibuat untuk bisa pergi ke rumah sakit yang tenggelam di laut itu, kan?
-그걸 모르고...
-미안한 건 나야.
-Sorry for misunderstanding.
-I'm the one who should apologize.
-Tapi, aku malah...
-Justru aku yang seharusnya minta maaf.
내가 계속 옆에 있었다면 카이토는 괜찮았을 텐데!
If I kept company with him, Kaito should have been fine!
Kaito malah terluka pada saat aku bersama dengannya!
병원에는 내가 갈게. 넌 카이토 옆에 있어 줘.
I'll go to the hospital. You keep company with Kaito.
Aku saja yang pergi ke sana. Kembalilah dan temani Kaito.
카이토하고 약속했어. 약을 가지고 돌아가겠다고.
I promised with Kaito. I'll return with a medicine.
Aku sudah berjanji dengan Kaito kalau aku akan kembali dengan membawa obatnya.
나도 갈게.
I'll go too.
Aku ikut juga.
카론도 같이 갈게뾰꼬!
Karon will accompany-pyoko!
Bawa Karon juga-pyoko!
-있잖아, 쇼우!
-응?
-Hey, Shou!
-Huh?
-Hei, Shou?
-Ya?
쇼우한테 약점이 있으려나?
Do you have a weak point?
Apakah kamu punya kekurangan?
-약점?
-공부도 잘 하고 운동도 잘 하고.
-A weak point?
-You do great in studies and sports.
-Kekurangan?
-Sudah rajin belajar, jago olahraga,
다리는 길고 멋지고. 여자얘들한테도 인기있고, 게다가 누나도 미인이잖아!
Your legs are long and you're popular among girls. On top of that, even your elder sister is beautiful!
kakimu panjang, dan kamu populer di kalangan anak perempuan. Ditambah lagi, kakakmu cantik!
-뭐야, 그게.
-뭐 없어?
-That's a weird way of praising.
-Told you, weak point-less.
-Enggak begitu juga, sih.
-Benar-benar tidak ada, kah?
어떤 야채만은 정말 싫어한다던가, 아니면 바퀴벌레를 보면 기절한다거나.
Maybe vegetable you really hate, or you will fell unconscious if you see a roach.
Mungkin sayuran yang tidak kamu suka, kah, atau begitu melihat kecoak langsung pingsan, kah.
-아니.
-역시. 쇼우는 완벽하구나!
-Nope.
-Doubtlessly, you're perfect!
-Tidak ada.
-Tuh, kan. Shou memang sempurna!
단지,
It's just that
Hanya saja,
누나한테 여러 폐를 끼쳤어.
I've caused a lot of trouble to my sister.
aku sudah sangat menyusahkan kakakku.
레나뾰꼬?
Do you mean Rena-pyoko?
Maksudmu, Rena-pyoko?
저 병원에 입원했을 때, 누나가 매일같이 찾아왔었어.
When I was hospitalized, my sister went to see me every day.
Ketika aku dirawat di rumah sakit itu, Kakak menjengukku setiap hari.
-입원?
-어릴 때 몸이 약했었어.
-Hospitalized?
-I had a weak body when I was young.
-Dirawat?
-Saat aku kecil, badanku lemah.
-아주 위험했던 때도 있었어.
-쇼우가? 그럴 거라고는 생각도 못 했었는데.
-There were some critical moments too.
-You had? Unbelievable.
-Katanya aku sempat mengalami masa kritis juga.
-Orang seperti Shou? Aku tidak percaya...
덕분에 약에 대해서는 잘 알게 되었지만 말이야.
Thank's to that now I have more knowledge about medicine than most people.
Tapi, berkat itu, aku jadi tahu lebih banyak tentang obat daripada kebanyakan orang.
자, 도착했다!
We're there!
Kita sudah sampai!
나와라! 데리트로스 몬스터 가니다라바!
Appear! Deletloss Monster Ganidaraba!
Muncullah, Deletloss Monster, Ganidaraba!
가니다라바: 타라바가니(레드 킹크랩)의 말장난
Ganidaraba: Pun from Tarabagani (Red King Crab)
Ganidaraba: anagram dari Tarabagani (Red King Crab)
힘내, 카이토!
Hang in there, Kaito!
Bertahanlah, Kaito!
빨리 오거라, 켄토. 오지 않으면 네 친구의 생명이 위험하지.
Come here right now, or your friend' lives are in danger.
Cepatlah datang kemari, Kento. Nyawa temanmu sedang dalam bahaya.
Brought to you by Subdiver
플래시를 발견했어뾰꼬!
I found flashlight-pyoko!
Aku menemukan senter-pyoko!
카론은 여기서 로프를 잡고 있어.
Karon, you hold the rope here.
Karon, tolong pegang talinya, ya.
그러고 있을게뾰꼬! 카론은 수영 못해뾰꼬.
I'll do so-pyoko! Karon can't swim-pyoko.
Siap laksanakan-pyoko! Toh Karon tidak bisa berenang-pyoko.
서두르자. 늦어버리면, 다시 바다에 잠겨.
Let's hurry. Before high-tide sink this place under the ocean again.
Kita harus segera. Kalau airnya pasang, bangunan ini akan tenggelam lagi.
야, 이상한 거품이 꼈어!
Hey, some weird bubbles are approaching!
Oi, ada gelembung aneh sedang menuju ke sini!
섬에 낀 거품은 류토 필드에 출현한 데리트로스 몬스터의 짓이다.
Deletloss Monster is responsible for the bubbles appeared on the island.
Gelembung yang mengambang di pulau adalah ulah Deletloss Monster yang muncul di Ryuto Field.
뭐라고?!
What?!
Apa katamu?!
서둘러, 켄토! 섬에 있는 아이들이 위험해!
Hurry up, Kento! Children in the island are in danger!
Bergegaslah, Kento! Kaito dan yang lain sedang dalam bahaya!
-류토 놈!
-켄토!
-That Ryuto!
-Kento!
-Ryuto kurang ajar!
먼저 가, 켄토. 좀 이따 나도 갈게.
You can go first, Kento. I'll follow you later.
Pergilah duluan, Kento. Akan kususul nanti.
-쇼우는?
-카이토한테는 약이 필요해.
-And you, Shou?
-Kaito needs the medicine.
-Lalu Shou bagaimana?
-Kaito membutuhkan obatnya.
지금 돌아가면 다음 썰물까지 기회가 없어.
If we go back now, there won't be any chance until the next low tide.
Kalau kita kembali sekarang, tidak akan ada lagi kesempatan hingga air surut selanjutnya.
빨리!
Go back right now!
Cepatlah pergi!
알았어.
Got it.
Aku mengerti.
매지컬 스테이션에 플러그 잇!
To Magical Station, Plug It!
Menuju Magical Station, Plug It!
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
긴급 발진 대기중.
Emergency dispatch, standby.
Siap untuk diluncurkan.
글라디온, 출동.
Gladion, shoot.
-녀석이 나타났어!
-그래, 해 보자!
-Right in front of us!
-Let's do this!
-Itu dia!
-Baiklah kalau begitu!
웹체인지! 글라디온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Gladion, Fighter Mode!
옥상으로 도망쳐!
Run to the rooftop!
Cepat lari ke atap!
그란발칸!
Granvulcan!
뭐야?!
What the?!
Apa?!
아직도... 안 돌아왔네뾰꼬...
He didn't came back yet-pyoko...
Masih belum, kah-pyoko...
쇼우! 죽으면 안 돼!
Shou! Don't die!
Shou! Tetaplah hidup!
제발! 눈을 떠! 쇼우!
Please! Open your eyes! Shou!
Kumohon! Buka matamu, Shou!
누나.
Sister.
Kakak.
늦어, 너무 늦어뾰꼬. 이렇게 되었으면 카론이뾰꼬!
He's being too late-pyoko. Karon will follow-pyoko!
Ini sudah terlalu lama-pyoko. Kalau begini, akan kususul-pyoko!
쇼우! 무사해서 다행이야뾰꼬!
Shou! Great to see you return safely-pyoko!
Shou! Syukurlah kau baik-baik saja-pyoko!
약을 찾았어.
I found the medicine.
Aku menemukan obatnya.
글라디온! 빅토리 모드!
Gladion! Victory Mode!
빅토리 글라디온!
Victory Gladion!
가자!
Let's go!
Ayo!
유우키 켄토. 게임 시작이다.
Yuuki Kento. Game start.
Yuuki Kento, game start.
류토.
Ryuto.
웹다이브! 가니다라바!
Webdive! Ganidaraba!
어디 해 보실까, 글라디온!
Show me your best, Gladion!
Mari kita mulai, Gladion!
그란블레이드!
Granblade!
가니다라바의 힘을 구경시켜 주지.
I will show you the power of Ganidaraba.
Akan kutunjukkan kekuatan Ganidaraba.
글라디온!
Gladion!
어떠냐? 이래도 움직일 수 있니? 자, 어쩔래, 켄토, 글라디온?
Was that menacing enough? Can you move now? What are you going to do now?
Bagaimana? Dengan begini kau tidak berkutik! Nah, apa selanjutnya, Kento, Gladion?
슬슬 체크메이트.
Checkmate soon.
Sebentar lagi sekakmat.
잠깐!
Stop!
Tunggu dulu!
웹체인지! 다이탈리온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Ditalion, Fighter Mode!
다이타 스매시!
Dita Smash!
쇼우!
Shou!
다이타 액스!
Dita Axe!
다이타 스매시!
Dita Smash!
지금이야, 켄토!
Now, Kento!
Sekarang saatnya, Kento!
빅토리 참!
Victory Slash!
형! 쇼우!
Brother! Shou!
Kakak! Shou!
형! 쇼우!
Brother! Shou!
Kakak! Shou!
카이토!
Kaito!
나...
I...
Aku...
잘 버텼네, 카이토.
You managed to be strong, Kaito.
Kau sudah berjuang dengan baik, Kaito.
이제 다행이야.
You're all right now.
Kaito sudah sehat sekarang.
고마워, 쇼우. 쇼우 덕분이야.
Thank you, Shou. It was only possible because of him.
Terima kasih, Shou. Ini semua berkatmu.
미안, 쇼우. 오해했었어.
Sorry about that earlier today, Shou. I misunderstood your intentions.
Maaf, ya, Shou. Aku sudah salah paham tentangmu.
역시 쇼우는 대단하구나!
Shou's great as always!
Shou memang luar biasa, ya!
맞아뾰꼬! 쇼우에게 약점은 없어뾰꼬!
That's right-pyoko! Shou does not have any weak point-pyoko!
Benar-pyoko! Shou tidak punya kelemahan-pyoko!
사실은, 나,
To tell the truth, I...
Sebenarnya, aku...
당근이 싫어. 기절할 정도로...
...hate carrots. To the poin I will faint.
tidak suka wortel sampai rasanya ingin pingsan saja.
그래, 쇼우?
Is that so, Shou?
Serius, Shou?
뭐야! 뭐 그건 나도 마찬가지야, 쇼우!
What was that seriousness for? Anyway same goes for me, Shou!
Ya ampun! Kalau begitu, kita sekawan dong, Shou!
류토 님, 다음 데리트로스 몬스터가 준비되었습니다.
Master Ryuto, next Deletloss Monster is now ready.
Tuan Ryuto, persiapan untuk Deletloss Monster selanjutnya sudah selesai.
Screenplay
Araki Ken'ichi
Storyboarding
Tokoro Tomokazu
Staging
Katou Shigeru
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Kurachi Shou
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Jean J. Jekyll
Nakai Masataka
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Kurachi Rena
Kakazu Yumi
Ryuto
Yoshino Hiroyuki
Lada
Nakamura Yuuichi
Voice Actor
Ditalion
Tobita Nobuo
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Thank you for watching!
Production
Preview for Next Episode
류토의 사악한 기운의 공격을 받은 우리는 출격을 할 수 없게 되어 버렸어.
After the Evil Aura Attack from Ryuto, we were disabled from going to fight.
Setelah diserang dengan serangan hawa jahat Ryuto, kami tidak bisa berangkat melawannya.
다행히도 카이토가 혼자 남아 우리를 구하러 와 줬어.
Thank goodness, Kaito managed to come to save us.
Saat itulah, Kaito yang tersisa bangkit untuk menolong kami.
지금 막 탄생하는 새 웹다이버와 함께, 글라디온이 한층 더 진화해.
With the new Webdiver, Gladion evolves once again.
Dengan lahirnya Webdiver baru, Gladion berhasil berevolusi kembali.
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !